Guide to the National Law Center records, 1865-2005 RG0014
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Law Center records
1865-2005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0014
120 Linear Feet
Collection includes the law alumni photographic collection, founder's day celebrations, biographical sketches, articles reports, GW law school yearbooks, 1895 to 1915, bulletins and journals of the Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute of GW, (1950-1972), copies of the "Advocate," Banners scrapbooks correspondence Alumni reunions, minutes from the Board of Trustees, Research notes, banners, caps and gowns, reports to the Dean Exam questions, and information on Stockton Hall.
Restrictions on Access
Series 12 is closed to research for 50 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the National Law Center.
Historical Note
The George Washington University Law School is the oldest law school in the District of Columbia. Originally established in 1826 by vote of the board of trustees of Columbian College (now The George Washington University), classes were discontinued just one year later due to insufficient enrollment and lack of financial support.
In 1865, the Trustees recommended the reestablishment of the Law School, and classes began in the Old Trinity Episcopal Church on Fifth Street between D and E. The Law School was to occupy this space until 1884. The Department of Law offered the degree of bachelor of laws, which required two years of study.
Sixty graduates, from 22 of the then 37 states, received degrees in 1867. The School continued to have a student body and a faculty that reflected its location at the heart of the seat of the nation's government. Supreme Court Justices David J. Brewer and John Marshall Harlan were among the many prominent members of the bench and bar who were on the Law School faculty.
In 1872, the Trustees adopted a resolution to establish a one-year postgraduate course in legal practice. That same year, Lydia S. Hall and Belva Ann Lockwood graduated from the National University Law School, the school's first female graduates. (The National University Law School, which had held an important place in legal education in the District since 1869, was merged into The George Washington University Law School in 1954.)
In 1877, one year after the first such program was adopted in the United States, the Law School instituted a course leading to the degree of Master of Laws. In 1891, the Intellectual Property and Patent Law Program was initiated, with the first course in Patent Law taught by the Commissioner of Patents.
The George Washington Law Alumni Association was established in 1912, and in 1914 the Department of Law became the Law School.
In 1924, Stockton Hall was constructed on 20th Street. Designed to house the Law School in total when it was built, Stockton Hall now is one of four buildings that adjoin to form the Law School complex occupying the block on 20th Street between G and H Streets, across from the World Bank and just four blocks from the White House.
In 1936 the Law School was made a graduate school and the degree of Juris Doctor was established. A baccalaureate degree was a prerequisite for admission to the J.D. degree program.
As its contribution to the war effort, GW maintained the third floor of Stockton Hall during 1941 for use by the U.S. Army Quartermaster Corps in testing fabrics for tropical use. In 1946, the Law School began accepting foreign attorneys into specially designed programs, and in 1948, Law School enrollment surpassed the one thousand mark.
In 1965 the International and Comparative Law Program was established. Two years later, the Law School library was able to consolidate its growing collection in the newly completed Jacob Burns Law Library. In 1970, the Environmental Law Program was introduced.
The Law School's Enrichment Program, which has annually brought such illustrious speakers as Supreme Court Justices Scalia, O'Connor, Kennedy, and Ginsburg; Senators Fred Thompson, George Mitchell, and Orrin Hatch; author Scott Turow; columnist George Will; FCC chairman Reed Hunt; ACLU president Nadine Strossen, and many others to the school, was established in 1981.
In 1984, Lerner Hall was completed and dedicated in a ceremony addressed by Chief Justice Warren Burger. In 2000, the Law School began a major building and renovation scheme to create an integrated, modern learning facility. The National Law Center became the School of Law in 1996.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include the law alumni photographic collection, founder's day celebrations, biographical sketches, articles reports, GW law school yearbooks, 1895 to 1915, bulletins and journals of the Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute of GW, (1950-1972), copies of the "Advocate," Banners scrapbooks correspondence Alumni reunions, minutes from the Board of Trustees, Research notes, banners, caps and gowns, reports to the Dean Exam questions, and information on Stockton Hall.
Collection Organization
Organized into thirteen series: five are simply titled National Law Center; three are National Law Center, publications; one is National Law Center, self-study; one is Hugh Bernard, papers; one is Department files; and one is Alumni Relations office.
Seminars; Scrapbooks; Stockton Hall; Courses and lectures; Conferences; Biography; Students; Washington (D.C.); Buildings; George Washington University--History; George Washington University. National Law Center; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; George Washington University. Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Foundation
- National Law Center, circa 1880-circa 1970; RG0014 Series 1; 1.0 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  17 photograph panels (36 x 29) of various law school buildings, 1880's-1970's.
  - GWU Law School, Fifth Street, 1865-1884; Series 1 (Item 1)
  - GWU Law School building, H Street, 1899-1910; Series 1 (Item 2)
  - "National University", undated; Series 1 (Item 3)
  - GWU Law School, 1435 K Street, NW, 1920-1925; Series 1 (Item 4)
  - Masonic Temple, 801 13th Street, NW, Law School on 5th and 6th floors, 1910-1920; Series 1 (Item 5)
  - University Hall, Law School classes held here, 1884-1899; Series 1 (Item 6)
  - Stockton Hall, undated; Series 1 (Item 7)
  - Law Library -- clearing of site, undated; Series 1 (Item 8)
  - Architect's drawing, National Law Center, 1967; Series 1 (Item 9)
  - Law Library construction, undated; Series 1 (Item 10)
  - Law Library lobby, undated; Series 1 (Item 11)
  - Law Library second floor study area, undated; Series 1 (Item 12)
  - Law Library second floor mezzanine stacks and study carrel, undated; Series 1 (Item 13)
  - Law Library construction, undated; Series 1 (Item 14)
  - Present-day Stockton Hall, undated; Series 1 (Item 15)
  - Law Library front entrance, undated; Series 1 (Item 16)
  - Architect's drawing, Law Library, undated; Series 1 (Item 17)
- National Law Center self-study, 1980; RG0014 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  Self-study of the National Law Center, including its history, governance, faculty (with resumes), students, cirriculum, library, alumni, etc.
  - Self-Study of the National Law Center, including its history, governance, faculty (with resumes), students, curriculum, library, alumni, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Law School scrapbook, 1898-1902; RG0014 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scrapbook of newspaper articles on the GW Law school. The materials range in date from 1898-1902.
- National Law Center, 1965; RG0014 Series 4; 1 Linear foot (Flat box 1)
  Banner for the centennial celebration of the law school, with GW seal.
  Formerly ACC# 904.
- Amicus Curiae, 1952-1968; RG0014 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet
  "Amicus Curiae," the Law School student bar association publication, became "Advocate" in 1969. The material ranges in date from 1952-68.
- Yearbooks, 1895-1915; RG0014 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of Law School yearbooks. They range in date from 1895-97, 1899, 1903, 1915.
  - Columbian Class-Book 1895- Law Class of 1895 (Volume 1)
  - Law Class- Columbian University, 1896 (Volume 2)
  - Columbian University Law School- The Class of 1897 (Volume 3)
  - Columbian University- Law Class of 1899 (Volume 4)
  - The Columbian- The Senior Class of the Law School of Columbian University, 1903 (Volume 5)
  - Res Gestae- George Washington University Law School Fiftieth Anniversary, 1915 (Volume 6)
- Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute, 1950-1972; RG0014 Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains the bulletins and journals of the Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute of GW. They range in date from 1950-72.
  - GWU Patent Policy, Washington DC Patent History, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Digest newsletter and Report to Members, 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Patent, Trademark and Copyright Foundation, Bulletin, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Patent, Trademark and Copyright Foundation, Bulletin, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Patent, Trademark and Copyright Foundation, Bulletin, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Patent, Trademark and Copyright Foundation, Bulletin, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Patent, Trademark and Copyright Research Institute of GWU, IDEA Bulletin, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IDEA Journal, Vol. 10 No. 2, Summer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IDEA Journal, Vol. 10 No. 3, Fall, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IDEA Journal, Vol. 10 No. 4, Winter, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - IDEA Journal, Vol. 11 No. 1, Spring 1967 Reprint of "Notes on European Opinion Regarding Industrial Property -- Summer 1967" by L. James Harris (Vol 11: No. 3, Fall 1967) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - IDEA Journal, article reprint Vo. 13 No. 3, Fall 1969, "Computer Software Protection: Report of an Institute Clinic" by Herbert R. Koller IDEA Journal, article reprint Vo. 14 No. 4, Winter 1970-71, "The Patent System in Distress" by Abe Fortas (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - IDEA Journal Vol. 15 No. 4, Winter, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - IDEA Journal, Vol. 15, Conference Number, 10/20/1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Advocate, 1969-1994; RG0014 Series 8; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  "The Advocate," newspaper of the Law School (called "Amicus Curiae" prior to 1969). The materials range in date from 1969-1985, 1989-1994.
  - Advocate, 10/20/1969-05/01/1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Vols. 1-5
  - Advocate, 08/27/1974-04/18/1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Vols. 6-10
  - Advocate, 10/20/1969-04/18/1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Vols. 1-10
  - Advocate, 10/1969-04/25/1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Vols. 1-4
  - Advocate, 08/30/1973-04/05/1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Vols. 5-8
  - Advocate, 09/13/1977-02/11/1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Vols. 9-13 (1983-85 are unbound)
  - Advocate, 01/27/1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Vol. 14: no. 11
  - Advocate, 11/25/1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Vol. 16: no. 5
  - Advocate, 10/16/1989-02/26/1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Vols. 21-24
  - Advocate, 1984-1994; Series 8; 1 Linear Feet (Box 8)
  - Advocate Vols 1-4 and 5-8, 1969-1977; Series 8; 1 Linear Feet (Box 9)
  - Advocate Vols 6-10 and 9-13, 1974-1982; Series 8; 1 Linear Feet (Box 10)
  - Advocate and Amicus Curiae, 1952-1974; Series 8; 1 Linear Feet (Box 11)
- Nota Bene, 2004-2005; RG0014 Series 9; .25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Law Center student publication, "Nota Bene". This newspaper ranges in date from September 13, 2004 to April 4, 2005.
- Hugh Bernard papers, 1865-1984; RG0014 Series 10; 27 Linear feet (Box 13, Box 8, Box 11, Box 17, Box 20, Box 19, Box 18)
  This series contains minutes from the Board of Trustees relating to the Law School, research notes, yearbooks, banners, caps/gowns, reports of the Dean, exam questions, scrapbooks, and files related to Stockton Hall. This material dates from 1865-1984 and was the former Law School Archives.
  Hugh Bernard was a law school librarian.
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Dean of the National Law Center, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Law School bulletins, 1900-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    1900-1980's, 1920-30, 1940-50
  - Faculty Senate Minutes on Meetings, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Faculty News Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Senate Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - One Copy of the G.W. Forum, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Copies of the Flaw Review, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Monday Report, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Lengthened Shadows", undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Copies of A University in the Nations Capital, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Advocates, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bernard's appointment notes, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Faculty Papers, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Publications of Law School, 1960-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Memorandums, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Meeting minutes, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Law School brochures, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Law School history, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Unrelated materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Law School Yearbook, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Law School Yearbook, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Law School Yearbook, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Law School Yearbook, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    3 copies
  - Law School Yearbook, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Law School Yearbook, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    2 copies
  - Amicus Curiae, circa 1950-circa 1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Related Materials, circa 1960-circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Directories, 1914-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Exam questions, 1921-1929 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - GW Magazines, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mall yearbook, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mall yearbook, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Mall yearbook, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Centennial banner, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Graduation cap and tassel, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbooks, records of the law school, 1925-1932 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Include meeting minutes, student rosters, grades, class schedules, degrees conferred, statistics.
  - Scrapbook of dedication of Stockton Hall, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cherry Tree, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cherry Tree, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Cherry Tree, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cherry Tree, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cherry Tree, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cherry Tree, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cherry Tree, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbooks, records of the law school, 1933-1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Include meeting minutes, student rosters, grades, class schedules, degrees conferred, statistics, etc.
  - In the Twilight of My Memory, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Lost Heritage, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Greenleaf and Law, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - A Bibliography of Materials on Legal Education, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Lawyers and their Story, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - A Lawyer's Story, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - America Revisited, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The Law Harvard, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The Law School at Case Western Reserve University, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Brigham Young University Law Review, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The School of Law- Columbia University, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Contemporary Author, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Professional School and World Affairs, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Processing and Storage of Viable Human Tissues, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbooks, records of the law school, 1941-1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 2 Hoods of Dean Wm. C. VanVleck, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Cap of Dean VanVleck, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Ceremonial Gown of Dean VanVleck, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Law School history, Trustees minutes, 1931-1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Law School history, School of Comparative Jurisprudence, 1891 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Law School history, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Law School history, 1980-1987 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Law School history, 1968-1976 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Law School history, 1953-1965 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Law School history, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Law School history, 1877-1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Law School history, 1926-1951 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Law School history, 1913-1925 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Law School history, 1897-1984 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Law School history, 1873-1926 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Law School history, 1865-1952 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Law School history, photographs, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Hugh Bernard, papers, 1961-1984 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Audio tapes of Bernard dictating history of GW Law School; certificate from American Association of Law Libraries (1961); woodcut of 17th century library; Luther Rice Society award (1971-72); James Moore Associates award; Reinhold Niebuhr serenity poem; American Bar Association Journal, July 1978; "Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity: A History"; "The Impact of the Environmental Sciences and the New Biology on Law Libraries"; "Universitas" newsletter of the University Professors for Academic Order, Inc.(1970-81); Realistic CTR-30B cassette recorder
- Departmental files, 1866-2001; RG0014 Series 11; 2 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  This series contains reports, bulletins, brochures, applications, press releases, posters, forms, faculty handbook, briefs, speeches, invitations, tickets, tuition payment book, directories, newsletters, publications, worksheets, papers, and programs. They range in date from 1866 to 2001. The materials concern annual reports, the Law library, plagiarism, admissions, Law School Admissions Services (LSAT), buildings, registration, reports of the Dean, faculty, fellowships, George Washington Law Association, the Government Contracts Program, the Government Contracts Institute, history, continuing education, graduate program, Law School, conferred degrees, Institute of Law and Aging, placement office, planning and development, citations, "Studies in Law and Economic Development", events, the Student Bar Association, Student Directories, student productions, the Patent Trademark Copyright Research Institute (changed to the Patent Trademark Copyright Research Foundation), conferences, the Charles F. Kettering award, the Department of Law and Jurisprudence, the Association of American Law Schools, policy and procedures, "The George Washington Law Association Bulletin", history, buildings, the Law School's centennial celebration, the International Law Center, patent law training, a patent petition for a broom, scholarships, fellowships, and graduates. Biographic information about Brigadier General David Sarnoff is also included.
  - Alumni, Law, 1950-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alumni, Law - Announcements, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni, Law - Announcements, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni - Law - Announcements, 1982-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni - Law - Biographical Information/Individuals -- Samuel Laing Williams, John Ray, 1990-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni - Law - Biographical Information/Individuals -- Cooper [Caftritz], Peggy, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni, Law - Reunions, 1950-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni, Law - Special Events, 1952-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Awards and Prizes - David S. Hendrick Memorial Prize in Insurance Law, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clubs, Societies, Organizations - Student Bar Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Convocations/Commemcements - Addresses - Law School, 1886-1891 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Convocations/Commencements - Commencements - Invitations - Law School, 1868-1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Government Contracts Program, 3/2/1966-4/29/1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - National Law Center, 1967-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Law Center - Admissions, circa 1964-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - National Law Center - Announcements, 1967-9 /26/1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Law Center - Awards, 04/16/1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - National Law Center - Buildings, circa 1968-04/19/2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Law Center - Conferences, Workshops, Symposia, circa 1962-08/25/1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - National Law Center - Courses, 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Law Center - Dean's Office - Report of the Dean, 1962-1969, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Law Center - Dean's Office - Report of the Dean, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Law Center - Dean's Office - Report of the Dean, 1977-1981, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Law Center - Dean's Office - Report of the Dean, 1982-1986, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - National Law Center - Faculty, 01/02/1953-11/28/1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - National Law Center - Fellowships, 1956-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - National Law Center - George Washington Law Association, 07/01/1985-05/16/1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - National Law Center - Government Contracts Program, 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - National Law Center - Government Contracts Program - Institute on Government Contracts, circa 1960-10/31/1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - National Law Center - Graduate and Continuing Legal Education, 1951-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - National Law Center - History, circa 1959-2001 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - National Law Center - Institute of Law and Aging, 09/30/1976-07/28/1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - National Law Center - J.S.D. Degrees Conferred, 1945-1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - National Law Center - Placement Office, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - National Law Center - Planning and Development, 10/15/1981-circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - National Law Center - Programs, 1963-04/1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - National Law Center - Publications, 12/19/1948-12/01/2000 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - National Law Center - Speakers, 04/05/1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - National Law Center - Special Events, 08/06/1964-11/15/1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - National Law Center - Student Bar Association (SBA), 1934-1999 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - National Law Center - Student Directories, 1968, 1970, 1982, 1984, 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - National Law Center - Student Organizations, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - National Law Center - Student Organizations - Black American Law Students Association (BALSA), 03/16/1991-04/01/1991 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - National Law Center - Student Productions, 1979-1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Law and Jurisprudence, Department of (1905- ), 03/1905-03/1906 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Law School, 1865-1959, 04/13/1920-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Law School - Dean's Office, 1865-1959, 12/1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Law School - Faculty, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Law School - Faculty - Abbot, Henry L. (Publication on the Panama Canal), 1899-01/1908 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Law School - Final Examination, 1867 and 1955, 1867-05/1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Law School - Graduate Program, 1865-1959, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Law School - Graduate Programs, 1996-1999, circa 1996-circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Law School - History, 1865-1959, 10/14/1868-09/1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Law School - History - Centennial (October 12, 1965), 09/24/1965-10/12/1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)